Tushar Iyer

CS System Administrator at University of Hartford

tushariyer@gmail.com

Summary

My name is Tushar Iyer. I love technology. I've been tinkering with computers since I was a child. I'm currently a 20 year old Computer Science student, but work as a System Administrator for the University of Hartford's Math, Physics, and Computer Science department. I also work as an International Student Ambassador for the Red Key Society at the University of Hartford.

Experience

International Student Ambassador, Red Key Society at University of Hartford

August 2015 - Present (3 months)

As a Student Ambassador, I am one of several ambassadors who interact with new incoming international students and help them prepare to move to campus by answering any questions or queries they may have. Another task is to help co-ordinate the International Student Orientation Program before the semester starts in which all ambassadors help new students assimilate to campus life. This was changed in August 2015 when all the ambassadors were brought under the label of the Red Key Society, which is an on campus organisation that works in Admissions.

CS System Administrator at University of Hartford

January 2014 - Present (1 year 10 months)

As a System Administrator, some of the tasks I have done with my team range from maintaining the computers used by students and staff in the Computer Science Department, regulating and maintaining the multiple servers dedicated to the department to finding and installing new hardware/software where needed.

International Student Ambassador at University of Hartford

March 2014 - August 2015 (1 year 6 months)

As a Student Ambassador, I am one of several ambassadors who interact with new incoming international students and help them prepare to move to campus by answering any questions or queries they may have. Another task is to help co-ordinate the International Student Orientation Program before the semester starts in which all ambassadors help new students assimilate to campus life.

Intern at Sagitec Solutions LLC

June 2015 - July 2015 (2 months)

As an intern at Sagitec, I was part of the Design Team. I was able to use my knowledge in HTML/CSS and JavaScript to help design and create components used in projects. I was also able to learn Photoshop and use it in my assignments.

Intern at MindShare Business Consulting Pvt Ltd

June 2014 - July 2014 (2 months)

As an intern at MindShare, I was taught my fundamentals for web-development. The company focused on SAP consultancy, and I was able to use my HTML knowledge to help assist in solving problems in a teambased situation as well as design concept web-pages to simulate what the finished product would look like.

Skills & Expertise

Microsoft Office

Microsoft Excel

Java

Red Hat Linux

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

PowerPoint

Microsoft Word

Photoshop

Public Speaking

Research

Teamwork

Social Media

Windows 7

Windows XP

Windows 8

Mac OS

Computer Maintenance

Education

University of Hartford

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, 2013 - 2017

Activities and Societies: Member of the ACM chapter at the University of Hartford [University of Hartford Computing Club]

Mercedes-Benz International School, Pune

High School, International Baccalaureate, 2008 - 2013

Activities and Societies: Model United Nations, Instructor for Extra-Curricular Badminton

Canadian International School, Bangalore

Middle School, 2007 - 2008

Hong Kong International School, Hong Kong

Elementary School - Middle School, 2001 - 2007

Activities and Societies: School Band

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency)
French (Limited working proficiency)

Courses

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

University of Hartford

Programming Foundations CS 111

Fundamentals of Computing I CS 114
Fundamentals of Computing II CS 115

Data Structures CS 220

Discrete Mathematics I M 221W

Foundations of Web Design & Development MWD 110

Principles of Macroeconomics EC 110
Principles of Microeconomics EC 211

Calculus I M 144

Rhetoric & Writing I RPW 110 (HON 182)

Foundations of Argument RPW 210
Introduction to Global Studies IS 100W

Power & Politics in America POL 110

US History since the Civil War HIS 131

Introduction to Film CIN 150

Introduction to Philosophy PHI 110
Intermediate French I FR 210

Intermediate French I FR 210
Cell Phones & Facebook Fys 100

Cell Phones & Facebook FYS 100

The Art & Thought of Classical Greece AUCA 120
The Caribbean Mosaic AUCC 150

The Adult Journey: Search for Meaning

AUCS 120

AUCS 120

Western Heritage AUCW 180

High School, International Baccalaureate

Mercedes-Benz International School, Pune

IB HL English Literature

IB HL History

IB HL Art

IB SL Mathematics

IB SL Physics

IB SL French

IB Theory of Knowledge